parexel.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy | Parexel

## Web Sites Privacy Commitment

### This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 2018

Parexel will collect information through its websites that can identify you (if provided by you), such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, company name and position. Parexel may use this information to respond to your requests for information, products or services. Parexel may also collect information that will usually not allow us to directly identify you, such as information gathered through "cookies" (see below).

When you contact Parexel via its websites to request or to access information, you are asked to provide your personal information. By providing your personal information to Parexel via its websites, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and to receive communications from Parexel.

The information you provide to us will be available to Parexel, its subsidiaries and third parties working with or on behalf of Parexel. Access to your information and the equipment processing it, is at all times restricted to appropriate staff. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, Parexel will not trade, sell, release, share or transfer your personal information for use by any business outside the Parexel organization without your consent, or in a form other than what was disclosed to you at the time the information was collected, unless permitted or required by law.

Parexel reserves the right to disclose all information collected to the extent required by law or to respond to judicial process. Parexel may also provide any or all collected information to a third party in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of the particular website to which the information relates if such third party agrees to treat all such information substantially in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Parexel takes reasonable measures to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information regardless of the country where such information is stored or transferred to.

In jurisdictions with data protection and privacy laws, and where contractual commitments require, Parexel ensures that individuals can exercise all relevant informational rights with respect to their personal information collected by Parexel via its websites, including, but not limited to, the right of access and correction, to withdraw consent at any time, object to data processing, request data deletion, restrict aspects of data processing, and request transmission of provided personal information in a common digital format (e.g., pdf) to themselves or another organization.

Please keep in mind that Clinical trial / study subjects must contact their investigator at their study site, who will be able to make the necessary link to subject identity as outside of Parexel`s own early phase clinical units, Parexel does not hold information that would allow Parexel to directly identify clinical trial / study subjects.

### International Data Transfer

Parexel has self-certified its compliance with both the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks. Please click [here](https://www.parexel.com/company/trust-and-privacy/privacy-policy/privacy-shield-notice) to view our Privacy Shield Notice.

Parexel is committed to the confidentiality, integrity and availability of personal information we process and has in place mechanisms to ensure a compliant transfer of personal information from the European Union and Switzerland to the U.S

### Information Security

Parexel maintains a reasonable level of physical, electronic and managerial procedures in order to protect the information that it collects from its website. This includes maintaining computer equipment, networks, programs and documentation to a common standard and restricting access to equipment and information to appropriate staff.

### Children's Privacy

Parexel does not collect or maintain information at its websites from those it knows are under 13 years of age, and no parts of its websites are structured to attract anyone under the age of 13.

### Links to Other Websites

Our websites may contain links to other websites. Please keep in mind when you access websites operated by other parties, whether through links on our websites or otherwise, that we do not control what happens on those websites. You should always check the privacy policy of the website you are visiting in order to be sure you know how the operator of that website will collect information from you and what the operator of that website will do with the information.

### Change Notification and Specific Privacy Terms

As we provide more services on our websites and as privacy laws and regulations evolve, it may be necessary to revise or update our Privacy Policy without notice. You can determine if this Privacy Policy has been revised since your last visit by referring to the "last updated" legend at the bottom of this page.  Your use of our website constitutes your acceptance of the terms of the revised Privacy Policy, and you should therefore review the Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that you are aware of its terms.  Please print, save, and retain a copy of the Privacy Policy (and of any revised version) for your records.

Please note that this Privacy Policy does not cover any Parexel affiliate or Parexel line of business that operates under its own separate privacy policy or specific privacy terms that are tailored for the different ways your personal information is collected by different Parexel lines of business such as:

  * Service Terms address customer data to which we may be provided access in order to perform services;
  * Recruiting Terms address information we may collect in connection with Parexel´s employment recruiting, clinical trial / study subjects or potential investigator efforts;
  * Marketing and sales terms address information we may collect in connection with marketing and sales activities; and
  * Specific web sites’ privacy policies address information we may collect via Parexel`s own early phase clinical units, or Parexel´s Academia.

### Inquiries, Complaints and Information Corrections

To be removed from our contact lists, or to make a complaint or submit an inquiry, please write to Parexel at the following address:

**Parexel International Corporation**  
Attn: Webmaster   
195 West Street   
Waltham, MA 02451, USA

Communications, queries or requests to exercise informational rights (e.g., access to data) or complaints can be addressed to the attention of Chief Privacy Officer, Parexel International GmbH, Am Bahnhof Westend 15, D-14059 Berlin, Germany, or emailed to privacy[at]Parexel[dot]com.

### Additional information for inhabitants of the European Economic Area

Communications, queries or requests to exercise informational rights (e.g., access to data) or complaints under the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (European Commission Regulation 2016/679 or GDPR) can also be addressed to the attention of Parexel`s EU Data Protection Officer, via mail to Parexel International GmbH, EU Data Protection Officer / Datenschutzbeauftragter, Am Bahnhof Westend 15, D-14059 Berlin, Germany, or emailed to EU_DPO[at]Parexel[dot]com.

Within the European Economic Area, individuals have the right in law to complain about how their information is handled to a supervisory authority (data protection authority) that is responsible for regulating compliance with the GDPR. A list of all EU supervisory authorities is available on the European Commission website: 

<http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>

### Cookies and Other Web Tracking Techniques And How We Use Them

When you use our sites, Parexel will assign cookie files (“cookies”) to you, which are a small amount of information we send to your web browser. Cookies enable the computers operating our websites to differentiate between visitors and to track the patterns of activities engaged in by different visitors. By tracking such activities, the computers operating our websites can recognize a visitor and customize certain features for that visitor. We may also use aggregated, non-identifiable information regarding persons who visit our site in order to learn more about the use of the site and how we can improve it.

You may be able to modify your browser preferences to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose not to accept cookies, you may not be able to use those functions of the websites that require registration.

We may also receive IP addresses in the normal course of the operation of our website. An IP address is a number assigned to you by your Internet service provider so you can access the Internet. Although we do receive IP addresses, we do not use them to identify you personally or disclose them to others.

This website uses the following web analytic tools. The tools use cookies to help the web team analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by the following companies under their privacy policies:

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

Cookie(s)

| 

Purpose  
  
---|---  
  
**Essential Cookies**  \- The site owner has indicated that these are essential to the running of the site.  
  
CONCRETE5

| 

This session id cookie remembers your recent page requests on our site and is required for the website to run. This cookie expires when you close your browser.  
  
__sharethis_cookie_test__

| 

Used to determine if cookies are supported  
  
**Non-Essential Cookies**  \- The site owner has approved these cookies but you may turn them off.  
  
Google Analytics                             

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
[Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)(<http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>)  
  
---|---  
  
Oracle Eloqua

| 

(<https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/index.html>)  
  
Evergage

| 

([http://www.evergage.com/privacy-policy/](http://www.evergage.com/privacy-policy))  
  
ShareThis

| 

(<http://sharethis.com/privacy>)  
  
Uberflip

| 

([https://www.uberflip.com/legal/privacy-policy/](https://www.uberflip.com/legal/privacy-policy))  
  
acuityplatform.com (auid)                               

| 

<https://acuityscheduling.com/privacy.php>  
  
adnxs.com (anj, sess, ssi, uuid2)

| 

<https://www.theguardian.com/info/privacy>    
  
ads.linkedin.com (BizoID, UserMatchHistory, lang)

| 

Used for LinkedIn Ad analytics (Advertising)

[https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?src=direct%2Fnone&veh=direct%2Fnone%7Cdirect%2Fnone#](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?src=direct%252Fnone&veh=direct%252Fnone%257Cdirect%252Fnone%23)   
  
advertising.com (APID)

| 

<https://policies.oath.com/xw/en/oath/privacy/intl/index.html>   
  
bidswitch.net (c, tuuid_last_update, tuuid

| 

Doubleclick.net (IDE)

| 

<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>   
  
exelator.com (EE, hsk_***, ud)

| 

facebook.com (fr)

| 

go.flx1.com (check, id, r)

| 

Advertising   
  
infolinks.com (ANUSERCOOKIE, __cfduid)

| 

Set to identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and to apply security settings on a per-client basis. For example, if the visitor is in a coffee shop where many machines are on the network, but the specific visitor's machine is trusted (e.g. because they've completed a challenge within your Challenge Passage period), the cookie allows us to identify that client and not challenge them again. It does not correspond to any user ID in your web application, and does not store any personally identifiable information.

linkedin.com (bcookie, lidc)

| 

<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>  
  
mathtag.com (uuid, uuidc)

| 

mookie1.com (id, syncdata_DBC, mdata)

| 

<http://www.mookie1.com/en-us/privacy.html>   
  
Pardot

| 

<https://www.pardot.com/legal>  
  
rubiconproject.com (khaos, put_***, rpb, c, rpx)

| 

Digital Identifiers created by Rubicon Project to aid in advertisements

scorecardresearch.com (UID, UIDR)

| 

Set by scorecard research are related to market research, and may track your behaviour on our website.

<http://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx?newlanguage=1>   
  
sharethis.com (__stid)

| 

Set as part of the ShareThis service and monitors "click-stream" activity, e.g. web pages viewed, navigation from page to page, time spent on each page etc. The ShareThis service only personally identifies you if you have separately signed up with ShareThis for a ShareThis account and given them your consent. You can read the ShareThis privacy policy here. This page also explains how you can opt out of the tracking aspects of the ShareThis Service if you wish to.

tribalfusion.com (ANON_ID)

| 

turn.com (uid)

| 

<https://www.amobee.com/trust/privacy-guidelines>   
  
v12group.com (mc)

| 

veinteractive.com (__ssid, DFAB3643-4FF1-410F-925C-FF7CB7CEFA97)

| 

Set to track abandoned transactions on our website

<https://www.ve.com/privacy-policy> .  
  
videoamp.com (vampid)

| 

<https://secure.videoamp.com/privacy.html>   
  
volvelle.tech (ouuid, ouuid_last_update

| 

<http://www.optomaton.com/privacy.html>   
  
youtube.com (PREF, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, YSC)

| 

Set by YouTube (Google) for storing user preferences and other unspecified purposes - <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>   
  
Salesforce.com

| 

Set to store information to track form submissions[https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy)
